Register of the Tom Mboya papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Government Series, 1957-1969
  Circulars, clipping, correspondence, legislative proposals, minutes of meetings and proceedings, petitions, and reports, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Member of the Legislative Council of Kenya, and as Kenyan Minister for Economic Planning and Development, arranged by physical form or subject in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  - Kenya Civil Service - Terms of Service (G/1). Report, 1959
    Box/Folder 39: 1
  - Localization of the Civil Service. Correspondence, minutes of meetings, and reports, 1960-1961
    - Volume one, (G2/v.1), 1960-1961
      Box/Folder 39: 2-3
    - Volume two, (G2/v.2), 1961
      Box/Folder 39: 4
  - Government Circulars (G/3). Circulars and correspondence, 1964-1969
    Box/Folder 39: 5
  - Correspondence with the Attorney General's Office (G/4). Clipping, correspondence, legislative proposals, minutes of proceedings, and petitions, 1965-1969
    Box/Folder 39: 6
  - Correspondence with the Police and Military (G/5). Correspondence and report, 1963-1964 (Reel 46)
    Box/Folder 39: 7
  - General Correspondence with Government Ministries (G/6). Correspondence, 1957-1960
    Box/Folder 39: 8
- Universities Series, 1956-1969
  Applications, briefing papers, brochures, clippings, correspondence, invitations, lists, minutes of meetings, newsletters, programs, research papers, reports, student photographs, and student records, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Member of the Legislative Council of Kenya, and as Kenyan Minister for Economic Planning and Development, arranged by name of institution or organization, or by subject in numerical sequence according to original file numbers. Includes materials pertaining to the student airlift programs initiated by Tom Mboya
  - University of East Africa (UE/1). Correspondence, invitations, programs, research papers, and reports
    - 1961-1966
      Box/Folder 40: 1
    - 1967-1969
      Box/Folder 40: 2
  - National Union of Kenya Students. Articles of association, communiqué, correspondence, minutes of meetings, platform, programs, reports, and speeches
    - Volume one, (UE/2/v.1), 1964-1968
      Box/Folder 40: 3
    - Volume two, (UE/2/v.2), 1969
      Box/Folder 40: 4
    - Volume three, (UE/2/v.3), 1968-1969
      Box/Folder 40: 5
  - Nuffield College, Oxford University (UE/3). Correspondence, 1956-1961
    Box/Folder 40: 6. Includes letters exchanged between Tom Mboya and Marjorie Perham
  - Roosevelt University (UE/3a). Correspondence, 1962-1964
    Box/Folder 40: 7
  - African American Students Foundation, Inc. Applications, clippings, correspondence, and reports, largely relating to the student airlift program initiated by Tom Mboya
    - Volume one (UE/4/v.1)
      - 1960-1961 (Reel 47)
        Box/Folder 41: 1
      - 1961
        Box/Folder 41: 2
    - Volume two (UE/4/v.2)
      - 1960-1961
        Box/Folder 41: 3
      - 1961
        Box/Folder 41: 4
    - Volume three, (UE/8), 1961-1964 (Reel 48)
      Box/Folder 41: 5
  - Cabinet Committee on Scholarships (UE/5). Correspondence and minutes of meetings, 1964-1965
    Box/Folder 41: 6
  - Kenya Overseas Scholarship Advisory Committee (UE/6). Correspondence, lists of recommended students, and minutes of meetings, 1962-1963
    Box/Folder 42: 1
  - Papers for United States (UE/7). Briefing papers and correspondence, relating to a trip by Tom Mboya to the United States, 1962
    Box/Folder 42: 2
  - Roberts Technical Trade School (UE/9). Correspondence, 1962
    Box/Folder 42: 3
  - Education - General Correspondence. Clippings, correspondence, and reports
    - Volume one, (UE/11), 1958-1967
      Box/Folder 42: 4
    - Volume two (UE/10)
      - 1964-1965 (Reel 49)
        Box/Folder 42: 5. Includes letter to Tom Mboya from Kenyan students studying in the Soviet Union, 1965 May 26
      - 1966-1968
        Box/Folder 42: 6
  - United States - Admission to Colleges (UE/12). Correspondence and newsletters, 1959-1960
    Box/Folder 42: 7
  - Correspondence with Students Overseas. Applications, correspondence, invitations, newsletters, and reports, largely relating to the student airlift program initiated by Tom Mboya
    - Surnames Starting with A, (UE/23), 1960-1968
      Box/Folder 42: 8
    - Surnames Starting with E, (UE/13), 1960-1969
      Box/Folder 42: 9
    - Surnames Starting with J, (UE/14), 1962-1969 (Reel 50)
      Box/Folder 43: 1
    - Surnames Starting with K, 1964-1969
      Box/Folder 43: 2
    - Surnames Starting with L, (UE/15), 1963-1969
      Box/Folder 43: 3
    - Surnames Starting with M
      - Volume one, (UE/16/v.1), 1968-1969
        Box/Folder 43: 4
      - Volume two (UE/16/v.2)
        - 1963-1965
          Box/Folder 43: 5
        - 1966-1967
          Box/Folder 43: 6
    - Surnames Starting with N (UE/18)
      - 1962-1963
        Box/Folder 43: 7
      - 1964-1969 (Reel 51)
        Box/Folder 43: 8
    - Surnames Starting with O
      - Volume one (UE/17/v.1)
        - 1963-1967
          Box/Folder 43: 9
        - 1968
          Box/Folder 44: 1
        - 1969
          Box/Folder 44: 2
      - Volume two, (UE/17/v.2), 1966-1969 (Reel 52)
        Box/Folder 44: 3
      - Volume three, (UE/17/v.3), 1964-1966
        Box/Folder 44: 4
      - Volume four, (UE/17/v.4), 1963-1965
        Box/Folder 44: 5
    - Surnames Starting with P, (UE/19/v.1), 1962-1965
      Box/Folder 44: 6
    - Surnames Starting with S
      - Volume one, (UE/19/v.2), 1962-1969
        Box/Folder 44: 7
      - Volume two, (UE/20), 1962
        Box/Folder 45: 1
    - Surnames Starting with T, (UE/22), 1964-1969
      Box/Folder 45: 2
    - Surnames Starting with Z, (UE/21), 1962-1966
      Box/Folder 45: 3
  - Student Requests - General (UE/24). Clippings and correspondence, 1963 (Reel 53)
    Box/Folder 45: 4
  - Applications for Overseas Studies. Applications, correspondence, and photographs, largely relating to the student airlift program
    - Volume one, 1960
      Box/Folder 45: 5-6
    - Volume two, 1960
      Box/Folder 46: 1
    - Volume two (Reel 54)
      Box/Folder 46: 2
    - Volume three, 1960
      Box/Folder 46: 3-4
  - Scholarships - General Correspondence. Correspondence, newsletters, and reports, largely relating to the student airlift program
    - Volume one (UE/7/v.1)
      - 1961-1962
        Box/Folder 47: 1
      - 1962 (Reel 54A)
        Box/Folder 47: 2
    - Volume two, (UE/7/v.2), 1959-1962
      Box/Folder 47: 3
    - Volume three (UE/7/v.3)
      - 1961 (Reel 55)
        Box/Folder 47: 4
      - 1962
        Box/Folder 47: 5
    - Volume four (UE/7/v.4)
      - 1963
        Box/Folder 48: 1
      - 1963 (Reel 56)
        Box/Folder 48: 2
      - 1964
        Box/Folder 48: 3
    - Volume five, (UE/7/v.5), 1961-1964
      Box/Folder 48: 4
    - Volume six, (UE/7/v.6), 1962-1964
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 48: 5
      - Nos. 101-200
        Box/Folder 48: 6
      - Nos. 201-300
        Box/Folder 48: 7
      - Nos. 301-400 (Reel 57)
        Box/Folder 49: 1
    - Volume seven, (UE/7/v.7), 1960-1961
      Box/Folder 49: 2
    - Volume eight, (UE/7/v.8), 1962-1969
      Box/Folder 49: 3
    - Volume nine, (UE/7/v.9), 1962-1969
      Box/Folder 49: 4
    - Volume ten, (UE/7/v.10), 1962-1969 (Reel 58)
      Box/Folder 49: 5
    - Volume eleven, (UE/7/v.11)., 1962-1964
      Box/Folder 50: 1. Includes correspondence unrelated to student scholarship programs
  - General Correspondence with William X. Scheinman (UE/8a). Clippings and correspondence, 1961-1962
    Box/Folder 50: 2
  - General Correspondence with Ben Odotte (UE/9a). Correspondence and receipts, 1967-1969
    Box/Folder 50: 3
  - Personal Correspondence concerning Dan Jumah Malowa (UE/10a). Correspondence and student records, 1962-1968 (Reel 59)
    Box/Folder 50: 4
  - General Correspondence with Friends Abroad (UE/11a). Correspondence and newsletter, 1963-1968
    Box/Folder 50: 5
  - New York University Medical Center (UE/12a). Brochures and correspondence, 1967
    Box/Folder 51: 1
- Miscellaneous Correspondence Series, 1953-1969
  Aide-mémoires, announcements, applications, bulletin, clippings, correspondence, invitations, itineraries, legal opinions, lists, minutes of meetings, newsletters, papers, press releases, reports, student photographs, student records, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Member of the Legislative Council of Kenya, and in various ministerial posts, arranged by subject in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  - General Correspondence - Nairobi. Clippings, correspondence, and reports
    - Volume one (MC/1/v.1)
      - 1961-1962
        Box/Folder 51: 2
      - 1963-1964
        Box/Folder 51: 3
    - Volume two (MC/1/v.2)
      - 1960-1961
        Box/Folder 51: 4
      - 1961-1962 (Reel 60)
        Box/Folder 51: 5
    - Volume three (MC/1/v.3)
      Includes correspondence relating to the East African Institute of Social and Cultural Affairs
      - 1963-1964
        Box/Folder 51: 6
      - 1965-1968
        Box/Folder 51: 7
    - Volume four, (MC/1/v.4), 1962
      Box/Folder 52: 1-2
    - Volume four, (MC/1/v.4) (Reel 61)
      Box/Folder 52: 3
  - General Correspondence with Others. Clippings, correspondence, minutes of meetings, and student records
    - Volume one, (MC/2/v.1), 1961-1967
      Box/Folder 52: 4
    - Volume two (MC/2/v.2)
      - 1960-1965
        Box/Folder 52: 5
      - 1966-1968
        Box/Folder 52: 6
    - Volume three (MC/2/v.3)
      - 1962
        Box/Folder 53: 1
      - 1963-1964
        Box/Folder 53: 2
    - Volume four, (MC/2/v.4), 1962-1963
      - Nos. 1-100 (Reel 62)
        Box/Folder 53: 3
      - Nos. 101-200
        Box/Folder 53: 4
      - Nos. 201-300
        Box/Folder 53: 5
    - Volume five (MC/2/v.5)
      - 1960-1961
        Box/Folder 53: 6
      - 1962
        Box/Folder 53: 7
    - Volume six (MC/2/v.6)
      - 1965-1966 (Reel 63)
        Box/Folder 54: 1
      - 1966-1967
        Box/Folder 54: 2
    - Volume seven, (MC/2/v.7), 1953-1964
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 54: 3
      - Nos. 101-148
        Box/Folder 54: 4
    - Volume eight, (MC/2/v.8), 1961-1963
      - Nos. 1-100 (Reel 64)
        Box/Folder 54: 5
      - Nos. 101-200
        Box/Folder 55: 1
      - Nos. 201-278
        Box/Folder 55: 2
    - Volume nine, (MC/2/v.9), 1969
      Box/Folder 55: 3
    - Volume ten (MC/2/v.10)
      - 1962-1968
        Box/Folder 55: 4
      - 1969 (Reel 65)
        Box/Folder 55: 5
    - Volume eleven, (MC/2/v.11), 1963-1969
      Box/Folder 55: 6
    - Volume twelve, (MC/2/v.12), 1966-1967
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 55: 7
      - Nos. 101-146
        Box/Folder 56: 1
    - Volume thirteen, (MC/2/v.13), 1968-1969
      Box/Folder 56: 2
    - Volume fourteen (MC/2/v.14)
      - 1967
        Box/Folder 56: 3
      - 1968
        Box/Folder 56: 4
      - 1968 (Reel 66)
        Box/Folder 56: 5
    - Volume fifteen, (MC/2/v.15), 1962-1969
      Box/Folder 56: 6
  - Requests for Financial Assistance. Correspondence and reports
    - Volume one, (MC/3/v.1), 1967
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 56: 7
      - Nos. 101-190
        Box/Folder 57: 1
    - Volume two, (MC/3/v.2), 1967-1968
      Box/Folder 57: 2
    - Volume three, (MC/3/v.3), 1968-1969 (Reel 67)
      Box/Folder 57: 3
    - Volume four, (MC/3/v.4), 1964-1968
      Box/Folder 57: 4. Includes correspondence unrelated to subject of financial assistance
    - Volume five, (MC/3/v.5), 1958-1969
      box/Folder 57: 5. Includes requests for speaking appearances by Tom Mboya
    - Volume six, (MC/3/v.6), 1957-1978
      Box/Folder 57: 6. Includes correspondence addressed to Pamela Mboya
    - Volume seven, (MC/3/v.7), 1967-1968
      Box/Folder 57: 7
    - Volume eight, (MC/3/v.8), 1967
      Box/Folder 57: 8
  - Complaints. Correspondence, party constitutions, petitions, press releases, and reports
    - Volume one, (MC/4/v.1), 1964-1966
      Box/Folder 57: 9
    - Volume two, (MC/4/v.2), 1968-1969
      Box/Folder 57: 10
    - Volume three, (MC/4/v.3), 1966-1968
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 57: 11
      - Nos. 101-133
        Box/Folder 58: 1
    - Volume four, (MC/4/v.4), 1957
      Box/Folder 58: 2
    - Volume five, (MC/4/v.5), 1962-1969
      Box/Folder 58: 3
    - Volume six, (MC/4/v.6), 1960-1963
      Box/Folder 58: 4
  - Personal Correspondence. Clippings, correspondence, and reports
    - Volume one (MC/5/v.1)
      - 1964
        Box/Folder 58: 5
      - 1965
        Box/Folder 58: 6
      - 1967 (Reel 68)
        Box/Folder 58: 7
    - Volume two (MC/5/v.2)
      - 1961
        Box/Folder 58: 8
      - 1962
        Box/Folder 58: 9. Includes typescript of autobiographical writing by Tom Mboya, "Short Biographical Note," undated
    - Volume three, (MC/5/v.3), 1963
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 59: 1
      - Nos. 101-222
        Box/Folder 59: 2
    - Volume four (MC/5/v.4)
      - 1960
        Box/Folder 59: 3
      - 1961
        Box/Folder 59: 4
    - Volume five, (MC/5/v.5), 1963
      - Unnumbered correspondence
        Box/Folder 59: 5
      - Nos. 223-300 (Reel 69)
        Box/Folder 59: 6
      - Nos. 301-394
        Box/Folder 59: 7
    - Volume six, (MC/5/v.6), 1964-1965
      Box/Folder 59: 8
    - Volume seven, (MC/5/v.7), 1962-1963
      - Nos. 1-100.
        Box/Folder 60: 1. Includes typescript of an article by Tom Mboya, "My Impressions of England," no. 75
      - Nos. 101-200 (Reel 70)
        Box/Folder 60: 2
      - Nos. 201-339
        Box/Folder 60: 3
    - Volume eight, (MC/5/v.8), 1963-1964
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 60: 4
      - Nos. 101-200
        Box/Folder 60: 5
      - Nos. 201-300
        Box/Folder 60: 6
      - Nos. 301-419
        Box/Folder 60: 7
    - Volume nine (MC/5/v.9)
      - 1957-1959 (Reel 71)
        Box/Folder 61: 1
      - 1960
        Box/Folder 61: 2
  - Invitations. Announcements, correspondence, and invitations
    - Volume one, (MC/6/v.1), 1966
      Box/Folder 61: 3
    - Volume two, (MC/6/v.2), 1965-1966
      Box/Folder 61: 4
  - Applications for farm manager (MC/7). Correspondence, 1967
    Box/Folder 61: 5
  - Hilton hotel project (MC/8). Correspondence, 1964
    Box/Folder 61: 6
  - Aziz Fancy (MC/9). Correspondence and legal opinions concerning the case of Aziz Fancy vs. Maganlal Hindocha, 1963-1964
    Box/Folder 61: 7
  - Dr. Eugene P. Link (MC/10). Correspondence and school records, 1962-1966
    Box/Folder 61: 8
  - Correspondence with Students* Overseas. Clippings, correspondence, and reports. *These materials consist largely of letters addressed to Tom Mboya by individuals outside of Kenya, for the most part non-students
    - Volume one (MC/11/v.1)
      - 1966
        Box/Folder 61: 9
      - 1967
        Box/Folder 61: 10
    - Volume two (MC/11/v.2)
      - 1960 (Reel 72)
        Box/Folder 62: 1
      - 1961
        Box/Folder 62: 2
    - Volume three, (MC/11/v.3), 1966-1972
      Box/Folder 62: 3. Consists largely of correspondence relating to Tom Mboya's brother, Alphonce Okuku
    - Volume four, (MC/11/v.4), 1957-1958
      Box/Folder 62: 4
  - Correspondence with Overseas Universities. Clippings, correspondence, and reports.
    Includes a significant amount of correspondence which is unrelated to universities
    - Volume one, (MC/12/v.1), 1963-1964
      - Nos. 1-100.
        Box/Folder 62: 5. Includes typescript drafts of two speeches by Tom Mboya, nos. 49 and 73
      - Nos. 101-200 (Reel 73)
        Box/Folder 62: 6
      - Nos. 201-291
        Box/Folder 62: 7
    - Volume two, (MC/12/v.2), 1964
      Box/Folder 63: 1
    - Volume three, (MC/12/v.3), 1965-1966
      Box/Folder 63: 2
    - Volume four (MC/12/v.4)
      - Nos. 1-100.
        Box/Folder 63: 3. Includes typescript of an article by Tom Mboya, no. 65
      - Nos. 101-200
        Box/Folder 63: 4
      - Nos. 201-300
        Box/Folder 63: 5
      - Nos. 301-345 (Reel 74)
        Box/Folder 63: 6
    - Volume five (MC/12/v.5)
      - 1960-1961
        Box/Folder 63: 7
  - Correspondence with Friends Overseas. Clippings, correspondence, papers, and reports
    - Volume one, (MC/13/v.1), 1963-1966
      - Nos. 1-200 (Nos. 74-183 missing)
        Box/Folder 64: 2
      - Nos. 201-304
        Box/Folder 64: 3
    - Volume two (MC/13/v.2)
      - 1960-1961
        Box/Folder 64: 4
      - 1961-1963 (Reel 75)
        Box/Folder 64: 5
    - Volume three (MC/13/v.3)
      - 1961
        Box/Folder 64: 6. Includes typescript of a paper by Tom Mboya, "Tensions in Development," undated
      - 1962
        Box/Folder 65: 1
  - Correspondence with Kenyans* Abroad. Clippings, correspondence, and reports.
    *Consists largely of correspondence with non-Kenyans
    - Volume one, (MC/14/v.1), 1966-1968
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 65: 2
      - Nos. 101-156
        Box/Folder 65: 3
    - Volume two, (MC/14/v.2), 1964-1966
      Box/Folder 65: 4
  - Invitations Abroad (MC/15). Correspondence, itinerary, and reports
    - 1965-1966
      Box/Folder 65: 5
    - 1967-1969
      Box/Folder 65: 6
  - Visitors from Abroad (MC/16). Clippings and correspondence, 1964-1968
    - Nos. 1-100 (Reel 76)
      Box/Folder 65: 7
    - Nos. 101-147
      Box/Folder 65: 8
  - Correspondence with the Embassy of the United States of America in Kenya, (MC/17), 1960-1968
    Box/Folder 66: 1
  - Correspondence with the United Kingdom. Briefing papers, clippings, correspondence, and reports.
    Includes correspondence with individuals from countries other than the United Kingdom
    - Volume one, (MC/18/v.1), 1963
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 66: 2
      - Nos. 101-200 (Reel 77)
        Box/Folder 66: 3
      - Nos. 201-300 (Nos. 220-279 missing)
        Box/Folder 66: 4
      - Nos. 301-369
        Box/Folder 66: 5
    - Volume two, (MC/18/v.2), 1962
      Box/Folder 66: 6
    - Volume three, (MC/18/v.3), 1965-1967
      Box/Folder 66: 7
  - Correspondence with the Soviet Union (MC/19). Aide-mémoire, correspondence, and press release, 1966-1968
    Box/Folder 66: 8
  - Correspondence with India and Pakistan (MC/20). Clippings and correspondence
    - 1956-1958
      Box/Folder 67: 1
    - 1959-1960
      Box/Folder 67: 2
  - Correspondence with Canada (MC/21). Clippings and correspondence, 1956-1960
    BOx/Folder 67: 3. Includes a biographical article about Tom Mboya, 1960 February 27
  - Correspondence with Spain (MC/22). Aide-mémoire, clippings, and correspondence, 1966-1968
    Box/Folder 67: 4. Includes printed copies, in English and Spanish, of two articles by Tom Mboya
  - Correspondence with Denmark, (MC/23), 1965-1967 (Reel 78)
    Box/Folder 67: 5
  - Correspondence with the Kenyan Embassies in France and Germany, (MC/23a), 1964-1969
    Box/Folder 67: 6
  - Correspondence with Australia (MC/24). Briefing papers, bulletin, and correspondence
    - 1964
      Box/Folder 67: 7
    - 1965
      Box/Folder 67: 8. Includes typescript of an article by Tom Mboya, "My Impressions of Australia," undated
  - Correspondence with Aborigines (MC/25). Article, bulletin, clipping, correspondence, and press release, largely relating to the aboriginal populations of Australia and Papua New Guinea, 1964-1968
    Box/Folder 67: 9. Includes typescript of an article by Tom Mboya, "Papua and New Guinea," undated
  - Correspondence with Israel, (MC/26), 1962
    Box/Folder 68: 1
  - Correspondence with Malta, (MC/27), 1963
    Box/Folder 68: 2
  - Correspondence with West Africa (MC/28). Correspondence, memorandum, press releases, and speeches
    - 1959-1960
      Box/Folder 68: 3
    - 1960-1961
      Box/Folder 68: 4
  - Correspondence with Mauritius, (MC/29), 1964-1968
    Box/Folder 68: 5
  - Correspondence with Nigeria (MC/30). Correspondence, invitations, press releases, and reports
    - 1966-1967
      Box/Folder 68: 6
    - 1968 (Reel 79)
      Box/Folder 68: 7
  - Correspondence with South Africa (MC/31). Correspondence, newsletter, and press release, 1960-1962
    Box/Folder 68: 8
  - Correspondence with Uganda (MC/32). Circulars, correspondence, and reports
    - Volume one, (MC/33/v.1), 1956-1959
      Box/Folder 69: 1
    - Volume two, (MC/33/v.2), 1959-1960
      Box/Folder 69: 2
  - Correspondence with Gambia, (MC/33), 1964-1966
    Box/Folder 69: 3
  - Correspondence with Ethiopia, (MC/34)., 1962-1967
    Box/Folder 69: 4. Includes letters exchanged between Tom Mboya and Haile Selassie
  - Correspondence with Rhodesia, (MC/35), 1965-1969
    Box/Folder 69: 5
  - Correspondence with Ghana, (MC/36), 1959
    Box/Folder 69: 6
  - Visit to Australia, 1964
    Materials relating to an official journey by Tom Mboya, in his capacity as Kenyan Minister for Justice and Constitutional Affairs
    - Volume one (MC/37/v.1). Newspaper clippings, 1964
      Box/Folder 69: 7
    - Volume two (MC/37/v.2). Articles, clippings, correspondence, itinerary, and reports, 1964 (Reel 80)
      Box/Folder 69: 8. Includes two articles by Tom Mboya: "We Are Neighbors - Australia and Africa," undated holograph, and "Australia and Africa Can Work Together," undated typescript
    - Volume three (MC/38). Brochures, bulletins, and itineraries, 1964
      Box/Folder 70: 1
  - Kenyans Abroad (MC/39). Correspondence, 1962-1968
    Box/Folder 70: 2
  - Visits - Kenya (MC/40). Correspondence, itineraries, reports, and requisition orders, 1964-1969
    Box/Folder 70: 3
  - Requests for Appointments (MC/41). Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Reel 81)
    Box/Folder 70: 4
  - Requests for Employment and Financial Assistance (MC/42). Correspondence, 1966-1967
    Box/Folder 70: 5
  - Honored Guest Lists (MC/42a). Correspondence, lists of invitees, and reports, 1963
    Box/Folder 70: 6. Consists of materials relating to the celebration of Kenyan independence, 1963 December 12
  - Correspondence on Development Projects (MC/43). Briefing papers, clipping, correspondence, minutes of meetings, and reports
    - 1968
      Box/Folder 70: 7
    - 1969
      Box/Folder 71: 1
  - International Group for Studies in National Planning (MC/44). Background paper, conference papers, statements, and program, 1966-1969
    Box/Folder 71: 2. Consists of materials relating to a conference in Caracas, Venezuela, 1963 November 15-22
  - African Elected Members' Organization (MC/45). Correspondence, minutes of meetings, policy statement, press statement, and reports, 1957 (Reel 82)
    Box/Folder 71: 3
  - Correspondence with Students*. Correspondence, speech, and reports.
    *Includes a significant amount of correspondence with individuals other than students
    - Volume one (MC/46)
      - 1962-1964
        Box/Folder 71: 4
      - 1966-1968
        Box/Folder 71: 5. Includes typescript of a speech by Tom Mboya, 1966 September 24
    - Volume two, (MC/47), 1961-1964
      Box/Folder 71: 6
  - Television Network (MC/48). Correspondence and reports, 1960
    Box/Folder 71: 7
  - Peace with Freedom, Inc. (MC/49). Correspondence, 1965-1968
    Box/Folder 72: 1
  - Correspondence with the Aga Khan, (MC/50), 1962-1967
    Box/Folder 72: 2
  - Rural Development Center (Kenya) Limited (MC/51). Correspondence and minutes of meeting, 1965-1967
    Box/Folder 72: 3
  - Nairobi Central Constituency (MC/52). Correspondence, 1964-1966
    Box/Folder 72: 4
  - Wings for Progress (MC/53). Correspondence and newsletters, 1967-1969
    Box/Folder 72: 5
  - World Citizen Party (MC/54). Bulletin published by movement headed by Garry Davis, undated
    Box/Folder 72: 6
  - Miscellany, 1960-1966
    Box/Folder 72: 7. Correspondence, press releases, transcripts of parliamentary proceedings, and speeches. Includes holograph and typescript drafts of speeches by Jomo Kenyatta and Tom Mboya, 1965-1966
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1962
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover. Not available on microfilm.